so let's answer our smt versus dual core
quiz we have a floating point intensive
thread
it's
going to use pretty much
these two issue slots
and very rarely use these and then we
have an integer only thread that only
gets to use these two so with the dual
core processor
one of the cores really gets to be
two issue plus maybe a little bit
another one gets to be just to issue
because it never sees floating point
instructions that it needs to have more
than two issue
in smt however
we would be able
to do
two instructions
from this thread and two instructions
from this thread per cycle so we will
getting very similar performance and as
we have seen then this is the more
effective approach because the cost that
we are getting
here
versus here is significantly lower so we
get similar performance for
almost half the cost here now
what would happen however if we didn't
have a floating point intensive thread
and instead got two of these
in that case the two core is slightly
more cost effective
because it gets the two issue
performance in each core
for twice the cost of one core whereas
this
gets us the performance of a single core
because both of these are sharing the
two issue slots for a cost that is more
than one core so in that case
this would be the more cost effective
option so as you can see it's not that
smt always wins over multiple cores it's
that it depends on exactly what types of
programs we have and exactly what's the
distribution of issue slots among units
and how different applications are using
it so the floating point intensive and
integer only and this type of a split
between issue slots is an extreme
example that makes the smt look really
good